<resources>
    <string name="app_name">MyPortfolio</string>
    <string name="title_activity_port_folio">PortFolioActivity</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="section_format">Hello World from section: %1$d</string>
    <string name="about_me"><![CDATA[Android application Developer with over 9 years of experience in developing Android applications. •Proficient in Agile methodologies to develop and manage product plans and timelines.  Technical Skills: •\tMobile Platforms: Android •\tProgramming Languages: Strong understanding of Java, Familiar with Kotlin, C, C++. •\tOS exposure: Linux, Windows, Android •\tDevelopment Tools\t: JDK, Android SDK,NDK •\tDebugging Tools: ADB •\tLibraries/framework\t: Volley,Butter Knife,Retrofit,Android Annotation,SQLite,JSON,XML,REST & SOAP •\tTools & Utilities: Android Studio, Eclipse, IntelliJ, Gradle, VersionOne (Agile tool), Jenkins, Bamboo, GIT, SVN •\tExperience in Test driven development. •\tAdditional Skills (Web related): Servlets, JSP,JDBC]]></string>
    <string name="skills">Working experience in developing Android based mobile application
Proficient in Agile methodologies to develop and manage product plans and timelines
Strong in Java programming &amp; has decent exposure to Kotlin as well
Better experience in using Android SDK tools &amp; APIs.
Better exposure to Android &amp; Java Design Patterns
Exposure to persistence handling using SQLite, Room, Realm &amp; MYSQL
Knowledge of  Firebase, REST , SOAP Web service integration to app
Knowledge of Spring &amp; Hibernate
Exposure to SOLID,DRY Designing concepts
Good exposure to Test driven development
Good understanding of Data Structures &amp; Algorithms
Good knowledge on MVC,MVP,MVVM &amp; Clean architecture
Good knowledge on Android architecture components
Familiar with basics of C, C++ &amp; Python
Exposure to knowledge of Web application development. (Java/J2ee)
</string>
    <string name="work">
        <![CDATA[As Senior Consultant at Capgemini Technology Services India Limited 1. BSH enabler apps, as part of the project execution, a custom launcher was developed for it and other project specific applications like Calculator App, Whether App, Notes App, Recipes App, Groceries app are developed to fulfill smart shopping user journey from the appliances. On the other User Journey called as connected Kitchen, inter connectivity between the appliances (where the Refrigerator can talk with a microwave) are planned using customized IOT cloud called as Kitchen Cloud.  Responsible for: • Understanding the client requirements • Involved in story planning, implementing and testing. • Involved in UI designing and developing the application using Android SDK • Implemented features like saving notes created by user etc. • Developed REST api as backend for testing internally with application using Spring MVC • Writing unit test cases • Documentation  2.Electric Vehicle Routing (Google map based Application) is a Google map based application for assisting driver in travelling from one place to another .Also suggesting driver of vehicle on information such as range ,available charging stations on the route suggested ,charge station details etc.  Responsible for: • Understanding the client requirements • Involved in story planning, implementing and testing. • Involved in UI designing and developing the application using Android SDK • Implemented key features like plotting route on Google map & charge station details UI • Writing unit test cases • Documentation       3. Fetal Monitoring System is an application developed on Android tablet for monitoring vital parameters of mother & fetal. Had features like alarm manager, displaying vital parameters on tablet.  Responsible for: • Involved in story planning, implementing and testing. • Leading team in development, code review & code maintenance  • UI development & feature implementation and verification through analysis. • Involved in customizing the application as per the requirement • Bug fixes and feature enhancements • Unit testing • Documentation of features implemented and enhanced • Helped team members to get familiar with MVP architecture through presentations & code     walkthrough. • Ensuring bug fixing for all owned features. • Helped QAs in writing Automation tests. • Following Agile practices to ensure feature can be delivered on time. • Responsible for peer code reviews and involved in pair programming.   As Developer at IG India \tIG Trading is mobile dealing app which provides users to Trade CFD, spread betting, Stockbroking on thousands of global markets. Responsible for: • Involved in UI planning, implementing and testing. • Ensuring deposit feature works from end to end by interacting with web services. • Responsible for implementing UI for Deposit feature in Payments section. • Responsible for implementing UI for Signal center list an insight into market for user to deal. • Ensuring live prices stream properly for each signal in list. • Enhanced Search feature for searching markets in application. • Ensuring bug fixing for all owned features. • Helped QAs in writing Automation tests. • Involved in adding/modifying Automation framework whenever required. • Following Agile practices to ensure feature can be delivered on time. • Responsible for peer code reviews and involved in pair programming.  As Senior Software Engineer at GlobalEdge  SharePoint client for Android is application by which user can do operations such as supported in desktop login. Check in, check out of document, watching lists and sites through navigation. Search for document or directory in specific site or list. Responsible for: • Designed and coded from specifications, analyzed, evaluated, tested and implemented. • Responsible for implementing SOAP client for android using KSOAP a lightweight and efficient     SOAP library for the Android platform used to consume web services. • Involved in UI planning, implementing and testing. • Implemented search feature to find files & documents stored in device and at server.  OS Upgradation  Responsible for: • Involved in implementation of feature named Tagging for Gallery and Music player application. • Ensuring bug fixing for Samsung Music player & Gallery app after OS upgradation.  As Software Engineer at Uttara Info Solutions \t Developed three Android applications namely Meter reading and billing app, Application form filler and signature capture app & WishStix (Pandoodle Corp) for two clients.  Responsible for: • Designed and coded from specifications, analyzed, evaluated, tested and implemented. • Developed uploading feature for the documents collected. • Involved in UI planning, implementing and testing. • Participated in client meetings whenever required. • Utilized Google’s Geocoding service to place markers on a map, or position the map. • Developed voice recording feature for the application using Multimedia framework using APIs. • Involved in integrating Facebook with the application. • Implemented Email sending feature using contacts provider. • WishStix is an entertainment application available in the Android Market.  As Software Engineer at SaaSTech Software \tWorked on reporting mechanism of Test Automation Framework for Web Applications  Responsible for: • Implementing Exception /Error handling feature of Framework. • Uploading Error details to database. • Integrating Framework with TestNG test Tool.]]>
    </string>
</resources>
